JACOB COLVIN

Platform, Site Reliability, and Software Engineer

ABOUT

My expertise lies in **Site Reliability Engineering**, enriched by a deep focus in **Software** and **Platform Engineering**. My passion lies in building robust **developer platforms**, crafting maintainable **infrastructure as code**, and architecting systems in a way that is simple and straightforward. My experience as a developer, with a focus on **Go** and **Python**, enables my ability to create platforms that are not only reliable and maintainable, but also enjoyable to use.

EXPERIENCE

EXPERIENCE		
84.51° / The Kroger Company	₱ Hybrid / Cincinnati, Ohio	■ May 2016 - Current
Senior Site Reliability Engineer		🛱 April 2021 - Current
 Successfully transitioned our Kubernetes (AKS) platform fro hosting multiple critical applications that were collectively r an on-call rotation to ensure compliance with SLAs. 		
• Designed a fully GitOps workflow for Kubernetes cluster m manual cluster administration work by over 1,000 hours pe		form, and Renovate, which reduced
 Rolled out Datadog as a unified observability platform for be OTEL Collectors for assorted telemetry pipelines; this enables saved over \$500k annually. 		
 Maintained multiple on-premise Cloud Foundry / Tanzu Apmoved applications from Cloud Foundry to Kubernetes. 	plication Service instances; supp	ported cloud migration efforts which
 Developed Python application for scaffolding template repos which collectively saved developers more than 3,000 hours 		
 Empowered developers to efficiently and independently trou observability platforms; headed support and maintenance of Thanos, Jaeger, Dynatrace, Fluentd, OpenTelemetry Collect 	of all observability tooling, includ	
 Developed Python library to centralize instrumentation for pprof profiling, with support for FastAPI, gRPC, Databricks experience with our observability platforms, and saved developed. 	notebooks, and more, which bot	
• Led development of multiple Prometheus exporters using leader election, CEL for custom rule evaluation, Cue and cu		
• Created multiple Jsonnet libraries for Prometheus and Aler	tmanager configuration, saving o	over 100 hours per year.
• Contributed fixes to Grafana , Thanos , Jaeger , and other up	stream Git repositories.	
Versatilist Engineer		📋 January 2020 - March 2021
• Created and administered multiple Azure environments usin resources such as Databricks workspaces, Datafactory insta		
• Enhanced our Prometheus ecosystem by adding high-availad Prometheus to track SLOs and KPIs over years instead of dis		Thanos, thus allowing consumers o
• Assisted a mix of seven development and data science team alerts, GitHub Actions , and Azure DevOps pipelines; acted		
ICT Co-op		
• Designed a C# API layer over several legacy systems, and improve velocity towards deprecation of legacy systems.	a SPA using TypeScript with Rea	act, to both assist with support, and
• Created a Prometheus exporter for SonarQube data, along team to gather relevant KPIs.	g with corresponding dashboard	s, rules and alerts, to allow security
Automated Red Hat Linux VM deployment through Service!	Now, via interactions with Satelli	te, vCenter, SolarWinds and Ansible
• Designed a custom web framework using PowerShell and and metrics from many distinct products.	Bootstrap for executing adminis	trative tasks and aggregating event
 Automated many miscellaneous tasks using PowerShell, \ workflows with Bash and SAS ODS. 	/BA , Bash and PL/SQL in Bash;	created and documented Automic
• Interfaced with BOSH and Hadoop to design custom Pivot	al Cloud Foundry monitoring solu	ution.
EDUCATION		

B.S. Information Technology, University of Cincinnati

🛱 Aug 2015 - April 2020

• Summa Cum Laude, CeDiD: 20H0-3K9Z-JEND

KEY PROJECTS

OmegaGraf	(jacobcolvin.com/OmegaGra
Officeacitai	\ \ \	Jacobcorvini.com/ Officgaon

- An open-source project that seeks to completely automate vCenter monitoring, by orchestrating a small ecosystem of containers, including Telegraf, Prometheus, and Grafana.
- Paper: https://scholar.uc.edu/concern/student_works/jw827c971
- Technologies: Docker, C# / .NET Core, TypeScript, React

Homelab MacroPower/homelab

- Infrastructure-as-code for my homelab / personal cloud. Defines multiple interconnected Kubernetes clusters, spanning across bare metal (Talos) and multiple Hetzner cloud environments (k3s-on-MicroOS).
- Technologies: Talos, Cilium, ArgoCD, Helm, Jsonnet, Terraform

- Just for fun, completely impractical tool that allows you to encode audio and video as Prometheus metrics.
- Featured on the Grafana blog:
- https://grafana.com/blog/2021/07/30/how-to-use-grafana-and-prometheus-to-rickroll-your-friends-or-enemies
- Technologies: Go, Jsonnet

- Grafana panel plugin that injects JavaScript into dashboards, which reports user session information to a backend Go server, which
 in turn exports Prometheus metrics for display in (you guessed it) Grafana.
- Over 1MM downloads, featured by Giant Swarm: https://www.giantswarm.io/blog/grafana-ception-or-how-we-do-grafana-analytics-giant-swarm
- Technologies: TypeScript, React, Go

- Prometheus exporter and Grafana dashboards for Wakatime coding statistics.
- Over 100k downloads
- Technologies: Go